



Hi! I'm a hacker, or at least I think of myself as one. I love to break down existing technologies and create new ones from

From the release of leap, oculus, and pebble to the release of the iWatch and more SDKs to come, you can always win my heart with innovation. Feel free to contact me if ever you want to hack something together.

the pieces. For this reason, I revert to the giddiness of my nine-year-old self whenever I get my hands on new tech.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

### Yuco Chimney Supply — Web Developer / June 2012 - May 2014

- Implemented user-based e-commerce website to manage transactions, online sales, and customer satisfaction.
- Developed administrator privileges and custom UI design for online marketplace using Spree Commerce (Ruby on Rails framework).

#### Stanford University — Teaching Assistant / March 2015 - Present

CS42: Contemporary Javascript (Spring 2015)

# PROJECTS & AWARDS

### DisTrac — TreeHacks Winter 2015 at Stanford University

Best Use of MongoDB and Top 10 Finalist

 A web application that allows users to track and visualize the spread of disease outbreaks and epidemics in realtime using user-based queries for outbreak reports, confirmations, and treatment diagnoses.

#### Commodisense — PennApps Spring 2014 at UPenn

Best Use of DigitalOcean, MongoDB Prize, and Top 10 Finalist

 A web-based application that offers a text-based interface for querying commodity prices and interactive data visualization.

### PharmFinder — Hack the Change Fall 2013 at UPenn

Third-Place Tie and Finalist

 A mobile application aimed at compiling pharmaceutical resources and connecting medical help assistants in Botswana with the proper outlets to direct patients to the medicinal products they need.

#### ReelNews — The Virtual Piggy Hackathon Winter 2013 at USC

Honorable Mention

 A web application that connects to news outlets, grabs recent articles, and smart parses each to provide a short summary of the article.

#### KitchenSitter — HackNY Hackathon Fall 2012 in NYC

 A web-based application that communicates with the Pearson Kitchen Manager API to grab recipes matching an inputted array of ingredients.

#### Nessle — Personal Project Winter 2014 at Stanford University

 An interface that allows users to connect to the internet—their Twitter, Facebook, and Google—through text-based queries.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Stanford University (CA), June 2018

B.S in Computer Science, Minor in M.E. GPA 3.725/4.000, Major GPA 3.750/4.000

**CS Courses:** Contemporary Javascript, Natural Language Understanding, Web Applications, Computer Organization and Systems, Programming Abstractions.

## **ORGANIZATIONS**

**CMO** — Stanford Investment Club

September 2014 - Present

Team member — Stanford Ski Team

September 2014 - Present

Member — Stanford Running Club

September 2014 - Present

Member — Stanford IoT & Robotics

December 2014 - Present

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript: Node.js, Angular.js, Meteor.js, React.js, Backbone.js, JQuery, Sails.js, D3.js, Three.js, Express.js.

Python: Flask, Django.

Ruby: Rails, Sinatra.

Java: Android, Spring.

PHP: Laravel.

Databases: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB.

Other: C/C++, Scala, iOS, HTML/CSS, Pebble, Leap Motion, Thalmic Myo.

Website: http://www.danxyu.com | Github: ../danXyu | Twitter: @yudan96 | LinkedIn: ../dxy96

Address: 531 Lasuen Mall # 15269, Stanford CA 94305 | Phone: (631) 965 – 0250 | Email Address: dxyu@stanford.edu